# 上次我在河邊溜達的時候 看到那個
Last time, when I was strolling along the riverside, I saw that the,
# 桑果啊
the mulberries,
# 熟了哦
had become ripe.
# 現在我們去摘一點
We're gonna pick some now,
# 帶了這個
together with this thing.
# 哇 有枇杷果哦
Wa! Loquats!
# 你看 這些枇杷
Look! These loquats,
# 那麼黃的枇杷都沒人吃 怎麼搞的
they're already golden yellow now but nobody picks them? What happened?
# 哎喲 又大又黃哦
Ayo! They're so big and golden yellow.
# 你看 這些
Look! These are,
# 我到都流口水
mouthwatering.
# 肉都是紅的 這個肉
The pulp is red, the pulp.
# 晶瑩剔透
Crystal clear
# 嗯嗯
Um um!
# 不知道誰家的
I have no ideas whose they are.
# 我都不知道這裡有一棵枇杷樹
I never knew that a loquat tree is here.
# 嗯 不好吃 好酸
Um! No good. It's so sour.
# 把那個相机拆下來
Take the camera out.
# 哎呀 這個來 扣下來
Aya! I pull them down, using it.
# 哪有摘不到的
There's nothing that I can't pick.
# 啊 這個好熟啦 這個都是
Ah! This is very ripe and this one too,
# 特別是這兩個
especially these two.
# 來 給你吃
C'mon! They're yours.
# 透明的哦
They're jelly clear, you know.
# 可以
Not bad!
# 吃枇杷是 這樣是最快的
Here's the fastest way to eat a loquat.
# 這樣
Let me show you.
# 不算 這個不算 這個有點壞啦
No, not this one. This one is a bit rotten.
# 把這稍微撕一下
Slightly peel it here,
# 然後一擠
and then squeeze.
# 這樣才快
That's the fastest.
# 所以
So,
# 吃東西要吃快來 要不然吃的很少的
when you eat, eat fast. Otherwise you would only have a pitiful share.
# 想要吃多點就要吃快一點
Always eat fast, if you want to eat more.
# 在上面
Up there
# 這個不要啦 放這裡
This one is no longer needed. Put it here.
# 路都沒啦
There isn't even a path.
# 要走水路的哦
We need to walk on the stream,
# 沒有大路走
as there's no proper path.
# 你看 這還有香蕉的哦
Look! Here are bananas too.
# 那麼小
They're so small.
# 小香蕉
Tiny bananas
# 迷你小香蕉
Mini tiny bananas
# 要從這裡上去
We need to go up from here.
# 你看
Look!
# 這個 很靚的哦
This is, beautiful, you know.
# 雖然小了一點 但是味道
Though it's a bit small, but it tastes,
# 很不錯
really not bad.
# 你看 手都紅的
Look! My hands are already red.
# 看到沒有
Can you see it?
# 一捏就
Squeeze it, and then,
# 紅的
it's red.
# 嗯 小的最好吃
Um! The small one taste the best.
# 嗯
Um!
# 你看
Look!
# 這麼
They're,
# 這麼熟了都沒人 沒人來摘
they're already so ripe now. But nobody, nobody picked them.
# 那不是天助我也
Isn't it a blessing from the God?
# 就快沒了哦
There are not so many left.
# 哎呀
Aya!
# 再來遲幾天的話 可能都掉啦
They would all fall down if we came a couple of days later.
# 啊 直接吃算啦
Ah! Let's enjoy them here right away.
# 嗯
Um!
# 這才過癮 這種就是不是很熟的 但是酸的
It's so much fun. These are not really that ripe, but a bit sour.
# 嗯
Um!
# 好酸不要
Very sour! Pass!
# 有熟的都不摘
Why not just pick the ripe ones?
# 還要吃紅的
I want the red ones too.
# 帶來這簍子又多
Bringing this sieve is com,
# 多此一舉啦
completely pointless.
# 你看 那裡好多
Look! There are a lot!
# 你要不要哦
You want some?
# 再不吃就沒啦
Now or never.
# 這個太小啦
These are too small.
# 這邊 這邊也有
Here, some more here.
# 你看 這種
Look! These are,
# 我們來遲啦 應該來早一點點
We are too late. We should have come a tiny little bit earlier.
# 來早一點 它剛好熟透
If we came earlier, they would be perfectly ripe.
# 現在是
Now they're,
# 就快掉啦
already about to fall,
# 更熟更透
more than just ripe.
# 這種很靚的
These are really beautiful!
# 以前我們還小的時候
In the past, when we were kids,
# 都是提了一個籃子來摘
we always picked them carrying a basket.
# 摘回 摘回去
We picked, picked them back,
# 一家人吃
for the whole family.
# 現在還沒 沒多少了現在一點點
Now it's still, there are not too many now, just a tiny little bit.
# 所以就算啦
So now it's no longer possible
# 自己吃飽就好啦
It's only enough feed myself.
# 這裡還有 這裡還有一棵
Here as well, here's another branch.
# 原先河裡面很多的
There used to be a lot by the river.
# 現在麼[SIC]多少啦
But not so many remain now.
# 不知道怎麼回事
I have no ideas what happened.
# 可能被
Perhaps they were,
# 被割 砍掉了吧
they were cut, chopped away.
# 這個現在 沒人吃
They're, now, nobody wants them.
# 人家現在都不喜歡吃這樣的東西啦
People don't like these kinds of stuffs nowadays,
# 就我們吃
we are the exceptions.
# 應該
I should,
# 挖點回去
dig out some of them back home.
# 我們養殖廠裡面種著
We can plant them at our site.
# 到時候想吃就吃
Then I can have mulberries whenever I want,
# 想甚麼時候吃就甚麼時候吃
every day, every minute, every second.
# 就這種 那麼小
These are, so small.
# 可能現在人看不上這種東西啦
They look so miserable to the people nowadays.
# 但是
But,
# 還可以喲
they're not bad.
# 反正我就喜歡這種味道
Anyway, it's the taste that I like.
# 那種 酸酸甜甜的
It's like, sweet and sour.
# 哎呀 那棵樹上
Aya! In that tree...
# 你看
Look!
# 整個是
These are all,
# 野桑果
wild mulberries.
# 正宗的
Authentic,
# 土貨
and locally grown.
# 可以喲
Not bad
# 味道還可以
They taste not bad.
# 明年的時候我們也
Next year, we need to,
# 來早一點
come earlier.
# 才能吃到更多
So that we can have even more.
# 現在都快沒啦
Not so many are left now.
# 好啦 我們去前面看一下
Alright! Let's have a look in the front.
# 全部搞定
Done here!
# 還不過癮
But I'm still craving.
# 你看 我的手
Look! My hands,
# 都變成這樣子啦
are already dyed.
# 哇 你看 這棵樹才多
Wa! Looks! This tree has the most!
# 坐下樹底下吃
Enjoying the fruits while sitting under the tree,
# 那才是最爽的
makes me the King of the World.
# 你看
Look!
# 站在藍天白雲下
Standing under the blue sky and white clouds,
# 吃著這個桑果
I'm enjoying the mulberries.
# 不知道
I'm running out,
# 沒詞形容 不會形容
running out of adjectives. I dunno how I can describe.
# 反正就是好吃
Tasty. That's it.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
The video ends here.
# 不能吃太多
It's not good to have too many.
# 我現在可能吃了有點多啦
I think I've already eaten a bit too many.
# 想上廁所
I wanna go to toilet.
# 這個
These are,
# 就像那麼
they look like,
# 吊燈萢一樣的 但是這個不能吃的哦
look like the wild berries. But they're inedible.
# 反正我就沒吃過 看上去就是是
I've never tried them. They look like,
# 很想吃的樣子 但是不敢吃
they look very tasty. But I don't dare to try.
# 不要中毒啦
I don't wanna get poisoned.
# 你看 兄弟種的這個李子樹 就長了一個的
Look! This is my buddy's plum tree. And this is the only single plum.
# 笑死我啦
I'm about to suffocate from laughing.
# 做個記號
Let me leave a marking.
# 就一個的
But here's just one.
# 做記號應該就不用了吧
I don't think I need any markings.
# 把這個遮一下
Let me cover it,
# 讓別人看不到
to hide it from other people.
# 這個李子刻字的話會把它刻傷的
I would damage the plum if I craft on it.
# 給它穿個衣服
Let me give it clothes.
# 遮風檔雨
A shelter
# 多靚啊 哦
It's so beautiful, isn't it?
# 你看 這樣一看它就是一個葉子 甚麼都看不到
Look! Now you see just a leaf, and nothing else.
# 到時候我們就來摘它
We can then come and pick it later.